<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-03-17T18:01:51-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">ANDY SHIMMIN</title><subtitle>Interaction Designer</subtitle><author><name>Andy Shimmin</name><email>andersonrshimmin@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Weeknote 3— Professional Twitter &amp;amp; Math</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/weeknote3" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Weeknote 3— Professional Twitter &amp; Math" /><published>2019-03-12T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-03-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/weeknote3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/weeknote3">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;craft&quot;&gt;CRAFT&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been talking with Wei wei a lot about the benefits of a Twitter presence. I know I’ve been overthinking the whole thing when catch myself staring into space thinking about what unique perspective I would bring to Twitter.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;twitter&quot;&gt;TWITTER&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been talking with Wei wei a lot about the benefits of a Twitter presence. I know I’ve been overthinking the whole thing when catch myself staring into space thinking about what unique perspective I would bring to Twitter.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;math&quot;&gt;MATH&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend recently gave me this math problem:
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;a-five-digit-number-in-the-decimal-system-has-the-representation-a-b-c-d-e-the-digits-abcde-indicate-in-this-order-the-respective-remainder-when-dividing-the-number-by-2-3-4-5-and-6-show-that-exactly-one-number-exists-and-specify-this-number&quot;&gt;A five-digit number in the decimal system has the representation a b c d e. The digits a,b,c,d,e indicate in this order the respective remainder when dividing the number by 2, 3, 4, 5, and 6. Show that exactly one number exists and specify this number.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I wish I knew even the slightest how to go about solving this problem. It took my friend multiple explanations to even understand what it was asking. He said it was a question from a 5th grade math championship. I hope to get to a point where I can solve these problems, because they are more a riddle than a math problem it seems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Currently reading: Cryptonomicon — pg. 247
&lt;br /&gt;
Currently listening to: Kazuashita - Gang Gang Dance&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Andy</name></author><category term="weeknote" /><category term="ux" /><category term="math" /><summary type="html">This week I build out my someday maybe collection, and contemplate a Twitter presence.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Weeknote 2— Craft and Revision</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/weeknote2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Weeknote 2— Craft and Revision" /><published>2019-03-08T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-03-08T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/weeknote2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/weeknote2">&lt;h6 id=&quot;craft&quot;&gt;CRAFT&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a lot of feelings around what craft theory means, but wanted some structure around the general consensus of its meaning. I was directed to this video titled &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=squHaZ9pinE&quot;&gt;The Invention of Craft&lt;/a&gt;, a presentation given at CCA by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.glennadamson.com/bio&quot;&gt;Glenn Adamson&lt;/a&gt;, the former Head of Research at the V&amp;amp;A Museum. It was a fascinating talk structured around craft through the lens of friction (woodworking), tension (textiles), and eccentricity (pottery). My biggest question after finishing it was, what separates this kind of craft from the craft of an expert coffee maker, or an Italian grandma making pasta? What makes something belong to craft, and another belong to skill in a given domain?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h5 id=&quot;craft-should-not-be-used-to-solve-a-problem-or-be-idealized-but-to-articulate-real-human-conditions-of-production-and-skill&quot;&gt;“Craft should not be used to solve a problem or be idealized, but to articulate real human conditions of production and skill.”&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;data-visualization-presentation&quot;&gt;DATA VISUALIZATION PRESENTATION&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put on hold this week and I tie up some other loose ends.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Currently reading: Cryptonomicon — pg. 247
&lt;br /&gt;
Currently listening to: Kazuashita - Gang Gang Dance&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Andy</name></author><category term="weeknote" /><category term="craft" /><summary type="html">This week I contemplate the beginnings of my knowledge of craft theory and the benefits of writing regularly.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Links for Data Vis Presentation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/dvrs" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Links for Data Vis Presentation" /><published>2019-03-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-03-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/dvpresnotes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/dvrs">&lt;p&gt;General Data Vis resources here: &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;if-the-moon-were-1-pixel&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://joshworth.com/dev/pixelspace/pixelspace_solarsystem.html&quot;&gt;IF THE MOON WERE 1 PIXEL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;international-picture-language-by-otto-neurath-1937&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imaginarymuseum.org/MHV/PZImhv/NeurathPictureLanguage.html&quot;&gt;INTERNATIONAL PICTURE LANGUAGE&lt;/a&gt; By Otto Neurath (1937)&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;the-madness-of-crowds-by-nicky-case&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ncase.me/crowds/&quot;&gt;THE MADNESS OF CROWDS&lt;/a&gt; By Nicky Case&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;stitch-fix-algorithms-tour-on-selecting-the-perfect-clothing&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://algorithms-tour.stitchfix.com/&quot; title=&quot;This was showed to me by Victor, a data scientist at Blend, about story based data visualizations. This is a particularly powerful example for me as it is wildly complex but has good animations and pacing to explain it in a thoughtful way.&quot;&gt;Stitch Fix Algorithms Tour&lt;/a&gt; on selecting the perfect clothing&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Andy</name></author><category term="data-visualization" /><category term="college" /><summary type="html">General Data Vis resources here:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Weeknote 1— Gathering My Thoughts</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/weeknote1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Weeknote 1— Gathering My Thoughts" /><published>2019-02-26T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-02-26T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/weeknote1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/weeknote1">&lt;p&gt;This is the first week of weeknotes, to hold myself accountable for making progress in my personal interests and career, but to also to see if I can last beyond this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;where-do-i-fit-into-design&quot;&gt;WHERE DO I FIT INTO DESIGN?&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week was the first time in months I felt motivated by the thought of design. After attending an “AEC disruption” panel, a discussion about the confluence of architecture and design in tech, I came to a couple of realizations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Design is a blanket term people like to use to hide their poor product decisions. So often I’m seeing people (PM’s, eng, and designers) drop words like “user testing” and “efficiency” and convincing others that what they did was intentional. I was reminded after this panel that I need to be aware of not doing the process because “that’s what you do”, but because it is necessary to have a better understanding of the problem at hand—if it’s even a problem to begin with!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There are so many small efforts I can make as an individual to create change in the grander scope. What’s that one saying? The seed doesn’t see the flower it grows? I’m still making a lot of connections between ideas as I transition out of college and need to respect my current pace.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For future Andy, small things that make a big difference include: Finishing the SuperHi courses you bought, writing things down instead of keeping them in your head, continuing to read books, and forming long term habits. As much as you tell yourself you’re in sapling phase, you’re still a bright aspirational seed in the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;sweat-bathing&quot;&gt;SWEAT BATHING&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m still reading up on sweat bathing. I just finished Mikkel Aaland’s chapter about the Turkish Hammam in his book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mikkelaaland.com/sweat.html&quot;&gt;SWEAT.&lt;/a&gt; I was able to experience communal bathing at the Kabuki Spa in SF’s Japantown. This spa has a mixture of many baths, including a hot and cold pool, a dry sauna, as well as a steam room. The idea of cleaning your body as an activity outside of your home is extremely foreign to me, but definitely underrated. Speaking of bathing being weird, In 1854, The Encyclopedia Britannica wrote about something called a “bath cabinet” for personal sweat bathing. I guess it’s so you wouldn’t have to bathe in a way that revealed yourself to others, but it looks more embarrassing than any amount of time in a communal bath, a probable cause for why it never gained popularity in America.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.mikkelaaland.com/images/privatesweats.jpg?crc=23608230I&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mikkelaaland.com/mediterranean-baths.html&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/a&gt; of Mikkel Aaland’s book SWEAT.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/small&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Anyway, I left Kabuki absolutely &lt;em&gt;radiant&lt;/em&gt;. I would love to visit other spas in the city to compare experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;data-visualization-presentation&quot;&gt;DATA VISUALIZATION PRESENTATION&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finished the second draft of a presentation I’ve been working on for how to visualize data. I have the structure in a good place but need to get feedback to clarify my thinking. The biggest challenge has been narrowing down all the examples I would like to include that have helped me understand DV better. Also so I’ll be able to talk about my perspective on DV without sounding like a maniac or needing 3 hours to explain everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Johannes and I also spoke about something very important to me that I’ve been revisiting all week: To study something as a craft, versus to study something as a discipline. To me, craft learning is from your own desire or interest in a topic, coming to conclusions based on your own observations and research; while a discipline is very externally driven by a “curriculum.” So a school for example. I still need to structure what I mean by craft and discipline, but for now I have a much better relationships with my craft-scaffolded knowledge.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Currently reading: Cryptonomicon — pg. 164
&lt;br /&gt;
Currently listening to: Caramelldansen (sorry)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Andy</name></author><category term="weeknote" /><category term="data-visualization" /><category term="sweat-bathing" /><category term="ux" /><summary type="html">This week I contemplate how I want to use design, my progress through Mikkel Aaland's SWEAT, and my presentation on visualizing data.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Blend: Transparency to Consumer Lending</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blend" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blend: Transparency to Consumer Lending" /><published>2019-02-21T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-02-21T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blend</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blend">&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#disclosures&quot;&gt;Disclosures Onboarding Tool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#okrs&quot;&gt;OKR Dashboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#product&quot;&gt;Product&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fl&quot;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blend/home-product.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;image made by Kaitlin Sullivan at Blend&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For NDA reasons, I am not able to show my work on the product, but instead I can show you some side projects I was able to produce during my time at Blend.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mortgage lending is a small and overlooked “area” due to the percentage of people who interact with loan applications or lenders regularly. Blend comfortably and confidently fits in this space, assessing the needs of both mortgage lending institutions as well as those applying for a loan, and making the process more accountable for both parties and overall more fluid and stress-free. My time at Blend as the first product design intern was filled to the brim with opportunities to learn about something I had never given a second thought— and ultimately, to help make  lending better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;disclosures&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;onboarding-tool&quot;&gt;ONBOARDING TOOL&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you can make a difference, you need to know the space your working in. This was perfect to educate myself as well as the rest of my peers on a small but very important facet in the application process—disclosures.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my first project, I created an onboarding tool as part of the new-hire onboarding experience that educated and refreshed Blend employees on a variety of mortgage and compliance related concepts. The bulk of this tool focused on an interactive demo of how mortgage disclosures— infamous for being tedious, granular, and a necessary evil for borrowers and lenders—operated within the ecosystem of lending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blend/disclosurespaper.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;I needed to map my thoughts before hopping into the computer. Each color represents a different perspective. ex: orange = borrower journey, pink = Blend, blue = disclosures, etc.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asking around, most of the questions were general, “What are the contents of a disclosures package?” “Why do we need them?” What compliance issues do they face?”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blend/disclosures.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final result had to be engaging enough for viewers to stay focused, but explained in a way so one could retain the information they were reading. The final result was a witty, interactive story of how Marc (with a “C”) borrower handled disclosures during his loan application. Feedback was clear that employees at Blend left knowing how disclosures fit into lending, how to design around them, and why they’re so important for the transparency of the loan application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;okrs&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;okr-dashboard&quot;&gt;OKR DASHBOARD&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OKR’s help to align a company toward actionable goals. Some may be ambitious, but they help inspire and steer employees at all levels in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project was devoted to amplifying that unity component, and making Blend’s alignment forward clear and simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blend/oldokr.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;Blend’s OKR Dashboard at the time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Blends current dashboard was hyper-straightforward with an intensity that lost all clarity in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first major problem was automation: How can we update these screens in a way that supports some visual design adjustments and automatic updating of the objectives? Having to manually update these numbers in Sketch each week was out of the question, but so was a Tableau dashboard that had negative hierarchy.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blend/okrdraft.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I explored ways in which we could maximize Tableau’s potential for visual clarity and sketched ways to call out changes in the data that showed the trend of each metric we were measuring— rather than a stand-alone data point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blend/solution1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After slowly crafting a proposed solution in Tableau, the design team and I collectively agreed that a successful OKR wasn’t about reorganizing the information. Rather, it was about educating Blend employees on &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; to look at the dashboard, not &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; to look at. As Ray, a product designer, mentioned, “Treat the OKR dashboard as a service design project.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blend/okrfoamcore.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It became clear that there were three phases to this project: an initial “educate” phase, the “update and inform” phase, and finally, a “take action” phase. The solution I had been working on only focused on updating and informing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked to analyze and understand what and how Blend needed to be educated on our company objectives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/blend/okreducation.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
  Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To address the “Educate” portion, I created an animated video describing each of the company’s OKR’s, and what they mean in a larger context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;product&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;borrower-experience&quot;&gt;BORROWER EXPERIENCE&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blend/blurry&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
Because of NDA purposes, I’d love to talk about my work with Blend’s new product offering in person. Thank you for understanding.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;fl&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;final-thoughts&quot;&gt;FINAL THOUGHTS&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blend was so accommodating with my own curiosities during my internship. From working on objectives one day, to an animated demo for a client onsite the next, I was thrown into a fast-paced environment that honed my ability to make connections from all faces of the company. My biggest take away was developing an understanding of how to listen to the needs of the company, and being okay with not knowing the solution. The lending industry is extremely ingrained in archaic processes, and learning about it was a huge undertaking— designing for it even more so.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Andy</name></author><category term="product-design" /><category term="ux" /><category term="data-visualization" /><category term="motion-design" /><category term="instructional-design" /><category term="visual-design" /><category term="research" /><category term="learning-design" /><summary type="html">Sample of projects as Blend's first product design intern working on their white-label SaaS platform, helping to deliver speed and transparency to the consumer lending ecosystem.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/blend/blend_splash.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Pink Themed Valentines Day Dinner</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/valentines-day-dinner" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pink Themed Valentines Day Dinner" /><published>2019-02-13T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-02-13T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/valentines-day-dinner</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/valentines-day-dinner"></content><author><name>Andy</name></author><category term="recipes" /><category term="food" /><category term="pink" /><category term="valentines-day" /><category term="cooking" /><summary type="html">Sample of projects as Blend's first product design intern working on their white-label SaaS platform, helping to deliver speed and transparency to the consumer lending ecosystem.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Undergrad Thesis: Interfaces For Online Learning</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/thesis" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Undergrad Thesis: Interfaces For Online Learning" /><published>2019-02-06T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-02-06T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/thesis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/thesis">&lt;p&gt;During the initial research phase of this project, I wrote an essay about linked memory-retrieval systems, both cognitive and machine-based, that help enhance pragmatic learning. Read it &lt;a href=&quot;/literature-review-thesis&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This is best viewed on a computer. There are a lot of videos that might not load properly on mobile.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thesis/splash.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#examples&quot;&gt;Existing Examples of “Learning Interfaces”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#prototype&quot;&gt;Prototype&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#learnings&quot;&gt;Learnings&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/thesis/ytvids.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
  Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve all been entertained by these videos; super clean, super simple, super &lt;em&gt;delicious&lt;/em&gt;, and easy to follow. And after we finish it, we have a tendency to click on another, and another, and another. Youtube rabbit holes are an easy thing to go down, and even though educational content is abundant online, it’s usually in the form of entertainment like this. We never call Youtube rabbit holes educational.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that’s okay, because if i wanted to learn about African animals except elephants I will find exactly what I need—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/thesis/elephants.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
  Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to find something online that teaches you something, but rarely is it shown through an educational lens. And that’s because an educational lens is a classroom, a teacher, other students, and the surrounding environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thesis/medium.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt; &lt;em&gt;Medium telling me what else I might like in the footer of the website. None of these are related to what I just read.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the internet isn’t that. It’s not any of those, Its a lot of “up next’s” and “suggested readings,” not based on what I’m currently doing, but based on my entire browsing history. So it needs to be up to the learner to mediate those resources online. In an age of abundant online educational media, it is important that we are able to treat these self-learning resources as something that we can shape and direct, rather than something that tells us to consume more of what it thinks we like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past year I have been trying to answer the question:
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-can-we-assist-learners-in-navigating-through-online-resources-effectively&quot;&gt;How can we assist learners in navigating through online resources effectively?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Through interviews with teachers, public speakers, students, academics, and hobbyists, I categorized my understanding of learning into three main questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do we effectively find and accept quality content from online resources in a sea of junk?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do we organize it in a way that makes sense to us?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;and how can we discuss this with others to deepen our understanding of it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thesis/model.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
and they all flow together as the process of learning happens.
This became the fundamental model for what learning should include during my investigation on this subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I researched existing examples of interfaces that have these categories, but found they tend to prioritize one, and struggle to navigate between each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets take a look at what interfaces do and don’t do well.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;examples&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;existing-examples-of-learning-interfaces&quot;&gt;EXISTING EXAMPLES OF “LEARNING INTERFACES”&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thesis/laptopyt.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Youtube is a great example of how an interface that has so much content for learning, isn’t presented in a way to support it. If I go to a video to learn about something, but I’m looking for ONLY the part I care about, I have to click through the entire video to find it. There are thumbnail previews, but that’s only a visual cue, so auditory explanations are not benefitted from that. If I want to discuss this with others, I have to leave the video and scroll down to the comments. If a comment is time stamped, I click and leave the comments to see the part of the video they were talking about, only to have to scroll back down to see the discussion around the snippet of video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a slightly different note, Google has an uncommon feature when searching some questions into it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thesis/whistle.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;where it gives you a &lt;a href=&quot;http://lmgtfy.com/?q=how+to+whistle&quot;&gt;suggested clip&lt;/a&gt;. Google will highlight specific parts of a video and tell you which moments in the video it believes are most relevant to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another is &lt;a href=&quot;http://watson.ted.com/&quot;&gt;IBM Watson’s TED website&lt;/a&gt;. Here, you can ask IBM’s Watson a question or topic and it will search every TED Talk for videos that it thinks are related to your inquiry. Just like the Google search, it clips the part of the video that is relevant to you, and starts the video from there, as you can see from the teal bar below the video. But this interface as well as Google’s suggested clip still just surfaces content for consumption, and neglects the other essential parts of a learning environment that people need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/thesis/2by2.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;digging deeper, I looked to different types of learning platforms to see how they dealt with this problem. It all varied based on what information you are looking for, and how deeply you want to understand it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resources like Youtube, Reddit and Quora have a wide breath of content, that is both academic and interest heavy, but are focused, based on their interfaces, on entertaining or consuming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resources that are educational and academic employ a classroom like setting, or a sequential learning style, with an emphasis on knowledge quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These two quadrants together have quality learning material, but because of the interface itself, we as learners aren’t empowered to retain this information through note taking or discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the other spaces, theres not many examples. But these are the two spaces that I see the most promise in, specifically, educational interest based learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;what-does-an-interface-for-learning-look-like&quot;&gt;What does an interface for learning look like?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Researching possible companies in that upper right region, I partnered with a company called Alcamy, who were working on a similar problem. Alcamy is a self learning platform that curates existing learning materials online so you can find helpful learning resources all in one place.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thesis/laptopalcamy.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their current website, which you can visit now, uses user created categories that filter entire topics into a streamlined curriculum. Together we worked to re-create their existing interface for one that promoted more than just consumption, so that if someone wanted to learn more about bitcoin, for example, they would find value in Alcamy whether they knew a lot or not much at all.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thesis/albert.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
Meet Albert, an avid bitcoin purchaser, he knows a lot about the basics, and he’s trying to learn about unstable currencies for his next crypto purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thesis/ridic.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
He’s really frustrated with his current attempts to learn about it on youtube and reddit, as he keeps getting video suggestions that steer him away from his topic through exaggerated titles and ostentatious thumbnails, and the lack of quality discussion in the comments prevents Albert from really diving deep into his topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/thesis/intro.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
  Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;prototype&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;prototype&quot;&gt;PROTOTYPE&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Alcamy, he finds the topic he’s looking for, and see’s Unstable Currency is already a discussion category. He is able to skip the sections about bitcoin he already knows and can immediately access Unstable Currencies&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/thesis/3sections.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
  Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the new interface, Albert has some additional tools to help him grasp this concept. and there are three columns to accompany Albert’s learning journey&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A place for note taking, where he can write down his thoughts, drag quotes and snippets, and have a place for him to help solidify his learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, a space for the actual content he’s learning from, and I will talk more later about navigating through it,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And lastly, a place for discussion with communities interested in the same topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While watching the video, Albert has questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/thesis/comments.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
  Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He writes a quick conversation starter, drags it over to the discussion section, and In no time, he get’s a clarifying response from someone else interested in learning about the same topic as him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the three part interface, Albert doesn’t have to keep scrolling between commentary and video like youtube and can focus on his learning over navigating. Which is critical during points when you are just starting out, as there is so much more to take in.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thesis/jane.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, like Jane, who knows nothing about bitcoin, she’s curious what all the buzz is about, and is looking to learn more. She’s found some great information watching TED talks, but is looking for a place to help her unscramble her thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/thesis/janecomment.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
  Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She starts from a beginner topic, and picks up the basics quickly. She’s can choose different ways to digest the content based on her preference. Jane jots down some notes and drags her comments to the notes section. Now, she’s interested in a certain part of the video, and grabs the scrub bar to refine the discussion a bit more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/thesis/msdetail.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The media scrubber, located directly on the video timeline allows Jane the ability to look at discussion and commentary from both the macro and micro level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/thesis/mscontext.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
  Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when Jane alters the scrubbers size and location, it filters the comments to just that part of the video rather than the video as a whole, allowing for more directed discussions that the long comment threads we’re used to don’t offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/thesis/scrubberuse.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
  Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She scrubs to a specific section to see what the discussion is about for that part of the video, only to find that someone asked her question! The response links her to another page, and she finds the exact quote that the commenter was referencing. she is able to copy the highlighted section directly to her notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;learnings&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;learnings&quot;&gt;LEARNINGS&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thesis/modelonui.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My work on learning interfaces aims to empower people to create meaningful relationships with their knowledge to support a mind of deep interest and curiosity, so that even the biggest problems can be deconstructed and understood. Looking at what defines an interface that helps someone learn is my step toward that. These two scenarios were looking at learning from a digital interface, but it stems far beyond just the digital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to bring my learnings from my work here with me in my future work, as i look at making technology not something that alleviates us in the moment, but supports us over time as we grow and develop ways to make education better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Andy</name></author><category term="learning-design" /><category term="visual-design" /><category term="motion-design" /><category term="research" /><category term="thesis" /><category term="college" /><summary type="html">There are a lot of resources and teaching styles that aim to educate, but they’re often presented as a form of entertainment rather than emphasizing the learning. This project investigated the qualities of the digital that assist or hinder learning.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/thesis/thesissplash.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Undergrad Thesis: Interfaces For Online Learning</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/thesis-process" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Undergrad Thesis: Interfaces For Online Learning" /><published>2019-02-06T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-02-06T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/thesis-process</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/thesis-process">&lt;p&gt;During the initial research phase of this project, I wrote an essay about linked memory-retrieval systems, both cognitive and machine-based, that help enhance pragmatic learning. Read it &lt;a href=&quot;/literature-review-thesis&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thesis/splash.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#examples&quot;&gt;Existing Examples of “Learning Interfaces”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#prototype&quot;&gt;Prototype&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#learnings&quot;&gt;Learnings&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/thesis/ytvids.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
  Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve all been entertained by these videos; super clean, super simple, super &lt;em&gt;delicious&lt;/em&gt;, and easy to follow. And after we finish it, we have a tendency to click on another, and another, and another. Youtube rabbit holes are an easy thing to go down, and even though educational content is abundant online, it’s usually in the form of entertainment like this. We never call Youtube rabbit holes educational.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that’s okay, because if i wanted to learn about African animals except elephants I will find exactly what I need—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/thesis/elephants.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
  Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to find something online that teaches you something, but rarely is it shown through an educational lens. And that’s because an educational lens is a classroom, a teacher, other students, and the surrounding environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thesis/medium.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt; &lt;em&gt;Medium telling me what else I might like in the footer of the website. None of these are related to what I just read.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the internet isn’t that. It’s not any of those, Its a lot of “up next’s” and “suggested readings,” not based on what I’m currently doing, but based on my entire browsing history. So it needs to be up to the learner to mediate those resources online. In an age of abundant online educational media, it is important that we are able to treat these self-learning resources as something that we can shape and direct, rather than something that tells us to consume more of what it thinks we like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past year I have been trying to answer the question:
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-can-we-assist-learners-in-navigating-through-online-resources-effectively&quot;&gt;How can we assist learners in navigating through online resources effectively?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Through interviews with teachers, public speakers, students, academics, and hobbyists, I categorized my understanding of learning into three main questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do we effectively find and accept quality content from online resources in a sea of junk?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do we organize it in a way that makes sense to us?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;and how can we discuss this with others to deepen our understanding of it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thesis/model.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
and they all flow together as the process of learning happens.
This became the fundamental model for what learning should include during my investigation on this subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I researched existing examples of interfaces that have these categories, but found they tend to prioritize one, and struggle to navigate between each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets take a look at what interfaces do and don’t do well.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;examples&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;existing-examples-of-learning-interfaces&quot;&gt;EXISTING EXAMPLES OF “LEARNING INTERFACES”&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thesis/laptopyt.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Youtube is a great example of how an interface that has so much content for learning, isn’t presented in a way to support it. If I go to a video to learn about something, but I’m looking for ONLY the part I care about, I have to click through the entire video to find it. There are thumbnail previews, but that’s only a visual cue, so auditory explanations are not benefitted from that. If I want to discuss this with others, I have to leave the video and scroll down to the comments. If a comment is time stamped, I click and leave the comments to see the part of the video they were talking about, only to have to scroll back down to see the discussion around the snippet of video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a slightly different note, Google has an uncommon feature when searching some questions into it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thesis/whistle.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;where it gives you a &lt;a href=&quot;http://lmgtfy.com/?q=how+to+whistle&quot;&gt;suggested clip&lt;/a&gt;. Google will highlight specific parts of a video and tell you which moments in the video it believes are most relevant to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another is &lt;a href=&quot;http://watson.ted.com/&quot;&gt;IBM Watson’s TED website&lt;/a&gt;. Here, you can ask IBM’s Watson a question or topic and it will search every TED Talk for videos that it thinks are related to your inquiry. Just like the Google search, it clips the part of the video that is relevant to you, and starts the video from there, as you can see from the teal bar below the video. But this interface as well as Google’s suggested clip still just surfaces content for consumption, and neglects the other essential parts of a learning environment that people need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/thesis/2by2.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;digging deeper, I looked to different types of learning platforms to see how they dealt with this problem. It all varied based on what information you are looking for, and how deeply you want to understand it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resources like Youtube, Reddit and Quora have a wide breath of content, that is both academic and interest heavy, but are focused, based on their interfaces, on entertaining or consuming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resources that are educational and academic employ a classroom like setting, or a sequential learning style, with an emphasis on knowledge quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These two quadrants together have quality learning material, but because of the interface itself, we as learners aren’t empowered to retain this information through note taking or discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the other spaces, theres not many examples. But these are the two spaces that I see the most promise in, specifically, educational interest based learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;what-does-an-interface-for-learning-look-like&quot;&gt;What does an interface for learning look like?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Researching possible companies in that upper right region, I partnered with a company called Alcamy, who were working on a similar problem. Alcamy is a self learning platform that curates existing learning materials online so you can find helpful learning resources all in one place.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thesis/laptopalcamy.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their current website, which you can visit now, uses user created categories that filter entire topics into a streamlined curriculum. Together we worked to re-create their existing interface for one that promoted more than just consumption, so that if someone wanted to learn more about bitcoin, for example, they would find value in Alcamy whether they knew a lot or not much at all.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thesis/albert.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
Meet Albert, an avid bitcoin purchaser, he knows a lot about the basics, and he’s trying to learn about unstable currencies for his next crypto purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thesis/ridic.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
He’s really frustrated with his current attempts to learn about it on youtube and reddit, as he keeps getting video suggestions that steer him away from his topic through exaggerated titles and ostentatious thumbnails, and the lack of quality discussion in the comments prevents Albert from really diving deep into his topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/thesis/intro.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
  Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;prototype&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;prototype&quot;&gt;PROTOTYPE&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Alcamy, he finds the topic he’s looking for, and see’s Unstable Currency is already a discussion category. He is able to skip the sections about bitcoin he already knows and can immediately access Unstable Currencies&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/thesis/3sections.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
  Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the new interface, Albert has some additional tools to help him grasp this concept. and there are three columns to accompany Albert’s learning journey&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A place for note taking, where he can write down his thoughts, drag quotes and snippets, and have a place for him to help solidify his learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, a space for the actual content he’s learning from, and I will talk more later about navigating through it,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And lastly, a place for discussion with communities interested in the same topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While watching the video, Albert has questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/thesis/comments.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
  Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He writes a quick conversation starter, drags it over to the discussion section, and In no time, he get’s a clarifying response from someone else interested in learning about the same topic as him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the three part interface, Albert doesn’t have to keep scrolling between commentary and video like youtube and can focus on his learning over navigating. Which is critical during points when you are just starting out, as there is so much more to take in.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thesis/jane.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, like Jane, who knows nothing about bitcoin, she’s curious what all the buzz is about, and is looking to learn more. She’s found some great information watching TED talks, but is looking for a place to help her unscramble her thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/thesis/janecomment.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
  Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She starts from a beginner topic, and picks up the basics quickly. She’s can choose different ways to digest the content based on her preference. Jane jots down some notes and drags her comments to the notes section. Now, she’s interested in a certain part of the video, and grabs the scrub bar to refine the discussion a bit more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/thesis/msdetail.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The media scrubber, located directly on the video timeline allows Jane the ability to look at discussion and commentary from both the macro and micro level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/thesis/mscontext.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
  Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when Jane alters the scrubbers size and location, it filters the comments to just that part of the video rather than the video as a whole, allowing for more directed discussions that the long comment threads we’re used to don’t offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/thesis/scrubberuse.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
  Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She scrubs to a specific section to see what the discussion is about for that part of the video, only to find that someone asked her question! The response links her to another page, and she finds the exact quote that the commenter was referencing. she is able to copy the highlighted section directly to her notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;learnings&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;learnings&quot;&gt;LEARNINGS&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thesis/modelonui.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My work on learning interfaces aims to empower people to create meaningful relationships with their knowledge to support a mind of deep interest and curiosity, so that even the biggest problems can be deconstructed and understood. Looking at what defines an interface that helps someone learn is my step toward that. These two scenarios were looking at learning from a digital interface, but it stems far beyond just the digital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to bring my learnings from my work here with me in my future work, as i look at making technology not something that alleviates us in the moment, but supports us over time as we grow and develop ways to make education better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Andy</name></author><category term="learning-design" /><category term="visual-design" /><category term="motion-design" /><category term="research" /><category term="thesis" /><category term="college" /><summary type="html">There are a lot of resources and teaching styles that aim to educate, but they’re often presented as a form of entertainment rather than emphasizing the learning. This project investigated the qualities of the digital that assist or hinder learning.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/thesis/thesissplash.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Lawllipop — App For Learning Foreign Laws</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lawllipop" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lawllipop — App For Learning Foreign Laws" /><published>2019-02-06T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-02-06T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lawllipop</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lawllipop">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/lawllipop/lawllipopsplash1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;&quot;&gt; &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/lawllipop/gameplay.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lawllipop is a social gaming platform that informs immigrants of important laws and regional customs. Play with your friends to learn about the essential information you need when traveling to a foreign country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/lawllipop/lawstat.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;!-- # **“** --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- #### I know so little, I just wish I knew more about how my taxes work, what my legal housing and labor rights are.
&lt;Br&gt;
*Druyvee* — **International Student** --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/lawllipop/Group.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;The websites for the Alcohol Policy Information System (bottom left), Justia (top left), free legal information for lawyers, and an excerpt from a California website on laws (right)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-might-we&quot;&gt;How might we…&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&quot;help-people-learn-about-the-law-and-cultural-norms-when-traveling-to-a-new-country&quot;&gt;Help people learn about the law and cultural norms when traveling to a new country?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&quot;bridge-divides-between-immigrants-and-the-laws-of-a-new-place&quot;&gt;Bridge divides between immigrants and the laws of a new place?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;70%&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/lawllipop/gameplay.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/lawllipop/splash detail.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/lawllipop/badge1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/lawllipop/badge2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/lawllipop/badge3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/lawllipop/lawscreens1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/lawllipop/lawscreens2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/lawllipop/img1.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/lawllipop/img2.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/lawllipop/img3.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Andy</name></author><category term="visual-design" /><category term="ux" /><category term="game-design" /><category term="play" /><category term="research" /><category term="motion-design" /><category term="civic-engagement" /><category term="college" /><summary type="html">Lawllipop is a social gaming platform that informs immigrants of important laws and regional customs. Play with your friends to learn about the essential information you need when traveling to a foreign country.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/lawllipop/lawllipopsplash.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Lawllipop — App For Learning Foreign Laws</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lawllipop-process" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lawllipop — App For Learning Foreign Laws" /><published>2019-02-06T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-02-06T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lawllipop-process</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lawllipop-process">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/lawllipop/splash.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#capa&quot;&gt;Competitive Analysis &amp;amp; Problem Areas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#prototype&quot;&gt;Prototype&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#learning&quot;&gt;What Makes Players Continue to Learn?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#exposure&quot;&gt;Public Exposure&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1,051,031&lt;/strong&gt; new legal permanent residents moved to U.S in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of these immigrants didn’t know a lot of important information about laws or customs unique to that region before moving to it. My group found that alarming and serious. There was an opportunity to assist travelers in a way that wasn’t stale or unengaging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My team and I asked 31 international students, families, and recent visa applicants about how they felt about the information they knew prior to moving to the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h3 id=&quot;i-know-so-little-i-just-wish-i-knew-more-about-how-my-taxes-work-what-my-legal-housing-and-labor-rights-are&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;“I know so little, I just wish I knew more about how my taxes work, what my legal housing and labor rights are.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
|                           |||
|—————–|——-|—|
|22|16|14|
|survey participants said they didn’t know the laws of a new country before moving.|people said they didn’t research laws before they moved.| participants mentioned they wanted to know about laws around housing, drugs, and starting a business.|&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;capa&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;competitive-analysis--problem-areas&quot;&gt;COMPETITIVE ANALYSIS &amp;amp; PROBLEM AREAS&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Looking online to try and understand the laws, people are quickly faced with a series of government text fields, whacky trivia, and a general scattering of the information they needed.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/lawllipop/Group.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;The websites for the Alcohol Policy Information System (bottom left), Justia (top left), free legal information for lawyers, and an excerpt from a California website on laws (right)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;there-isnt-a-place-to-learn-laws-in-an-easy-and-digestible-way&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;There isn’t a place to learn laws in an easy and digestible way.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How might we…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Help people learn about the law and cultural norms when traveling to a new country?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Bridge divides between immigrants and the laws of a new place?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;prototype&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;prototype&quot;&gt;PROTOTYPE&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;70%&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/lawllipop/gameplay.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;If the video isn’t playing, right click it to ‘Show Controls’, you can view it from there.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/lawllipop/splash detail.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;learning&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;what-makes-players-continue-to-learn&quot;&gt;WHAT MAKES PLAYERS CONTINUE TO LEARN?&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/lawllipop/badge1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/lawllipop/badge2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/lawllipop/badge3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a name=&quot;exposure&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;public-exposure&quot;&gt;PUBLIC EXPOSURE&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Touchpoints and consumables in airports, car rental agencies, and airline pouches will reach our audience in critical locations to spread the word about our product.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/lawllipop/img1.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/lawllipop/img2.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/lawllipop/img3.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Andy</name></author><category term="visual-design" /><category term="ux" /><category term="game-design" /><category term="play" /><category term="research" /><category term="motion-design" /><category term="civic-engagement" /><category term="college" /><summary type="html">Lawllipop is a social gaming platform that informs immigrants of important laws and regional customs. Play with your friends to learn about the essential information you need when traveling to a foreign country.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/lawllipop/lawllipopsplash.png" /></entry></feed>